<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>velero on Veerendra&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://veerendra2.github.io/tags/velero/</link>
    <description>Recent content in velero on Veerendra&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veerendra2.github.io/tags/velero/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strimzi Kafka Disaster Recovery with Velero</title>
      <link>https://veerendra2.github.io/strimzi-kafka-disaster-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veerendra2.github.io/strimzi-kafka-disaster-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello my dear fellow humans, hope you are having a great day. Today&amp;rsquo;s guide is on how to recover from a disaster for Strimzi Kafka with Velero. First of all, what is Strmzi Kafka?
https://strimzi.io
Strimzi provides a way to run an Apache Kafka cluster on Kubernetes in various deployment configurations.
Back in a while, I worked on Strimzi Kafka deployment on Openshift, very easy to set up and manage production-level Kafka cluster on Kubernetes, I have to give credit to the Strimzi project team, did a great job on documentation, support on Github discussions and active developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velero Deployment with Kustomize (Azure)</title>
      <link>https://veerendra2.github.io/velero-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veerendra2.github.io/velero-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello guys, today I came up with an interesting write-up, that is how to set up backup and restore with Velero on Kubernetes. A year back I worked on Strimzi Kafka, a deployment solution for deploying production-level Kafka on Kubernetes. Strimzi Kafka uses persistance volume(PV) as a disk which is a managed disk from a cloud provider(e.g. Azure, AWS, etc), but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a proper backup solution in order to configure PV backup and restore.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
